<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internship on Abhishek Verma</title>
    <link>https://abhi608.github.io/tags/internship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internship on Abhishek Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Abhishek Verma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abhi608.github.io/tags/internship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elanic Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/elanic-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/elanic-intern/</guid>
      <description> NodeJS Development Nov&amp;rsquo;15 - Dec&amp;rsquo;15
Mentor: Pragyan Tripathi, CTO, Elanic
 Full Stack Development: Elasticsearch, MongoDB and NodeJS with Restify framework. Indexed all the data to Elasticsearch from MongoDB and builtREST APIs for search queries.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShareChat Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/sharechat-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/sharechat-intern/</guid>
      <description>Full Stack Development May&amp;rsquo;16 - July&amp;rsquo;16
Mentor: Bhanu Singh, CTO, ShareChat
 Worked on Mixpanel API to get data about the Mobile Application and used D3.js(Data Driven Documents), a data visualisation tool to convert raw data to presentable form. Data included retention and engagement cohorts. Was part of a 3 member team which whose responsibility was making, maintaining and deploying anandroid app which featured as Top Free in the Google Play Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineer at VISA</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-fte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-fte/</guid>
      <description>My Responsibilities at VISA July&amp;rsquo;18 - Present
Manager: Mr. Dumesh Nair, Director of Software Engineering at VISA
 Responsibilities include designing, implementing and maintaining large scale distributed systems used in everyday payment transactions. Worked on detecting the future possibility of deadlock during parallel processing and dynamically changing the resource allocation algorithm. Designed and implemented Least Cost Routing(minimum possible fees paid by VISA) for debit and credit card transactions in a new sale service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VISA Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-intern/</guid>
      <description>My Projects at VISA Self-Heling Automation May&amp;rsquo;17 - July&amp;rsquo;17
Manager: Mr. Mohan Babu Nellore, Director-MAP
Mentor: Mr. Arup Datta
 Implemented an intelligent automation architecture that makes sure all dependent components (VMs, services/applications, databases) are working as desired before running actual test suite to wipe off all false positives. This ensured that there is no downtimefor any service/API and also reduced development and test time by 90%. Implemented Restful APIs for application health-check, starting/stopping and re-starting the services using JAVA servlet framework.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>