<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Abhishek Verma</title>
    <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Abhishek Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Abhishek Verma</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abhi608.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain &amp; Consensus Protocols</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Arnab Bhattacharya, IITK
Stretch: Aug&amp;rsquo;17 - Nov&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: Blockchain Technology
Explored various aspects of blockchains. Major field of study was consensus protocols based on concepts like Proof of Work, Proof of Stake and Proof of Space. Also covered Algorand and did a case study of Bitcoin and ZCash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C to MIPS Compiler</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/compiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/compiler/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Amey Karkare, IITK
Stretch: Jan&amp;rsquo;17 - Apr&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: C to MIPS Compiler
Developed a C compiler that compiles to MIPS, implemented using Python. Implemented all stages of compiler design - lexer, parser, intermediate code generator and code generator. Handled a variety of semantic and syntactic errors using translation schemes. Built support for recursion, struct as parameter and return value, short circuit evaluation and other optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chat Application using Socket Programming</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/socket/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Dheeraj Sanghi, IITK
Stretch: Oct&amp;rsquo;17 - Nov&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: ChatApp using Socket Programming
Created a chat application using socket programming in python. Implemented a concurrent server with slaves listening for any incoming connection. Application provides various facilities such as SignUp, Login, Logout, Block/Unblock, Private/Broadcast messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatbot Development</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Programming Club, IITK
Stretch: May&amp;rsquo;15 - July&amp;rsquo;15
Complete Project: Chatbot
Developed a chatbot, called IVANA which behaved like humans. Used the Natural Language Toolkit(NLTK) library of Python to implement NLP techniques. Designed and implemented three distinct algorithms using N-Grams, WordNet and Part-of-Speech tagging in english language. Database handling was done in MySQL. Also, a visual app was deployed for the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combinatorial Game Theory</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/combinatorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/combinatorial/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Rajat Mittal, IITK
Stretch: Sep&amp;rsquo;15 - Nov&amp;rsquo;15
Complete Project: Combinatorial Game Theory
Studied the basic concepts of combinatorial game theory and the analysis of various games like Nim, Hex and Tic Tac Toe. Studied the mathematical treatment of games and some of the results that can be derived from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of Prutor - An interface to indroduce people to the world of programming</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/prutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/prutor/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Amey Karkare, IITK
Stretch: Jan&amp;rsquo;17 - Apr&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: Prutor Interface
Added admin side modules and features to Prutor, a Node.js platform used to teach programming to 800 first year students every year in IIT Kanpur. Worked on Node.js, SQL, HTML and CSS like technologies. Used docker to run all the services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Atari Game strategies using Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/atari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/atari/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Piyush Rai, IITK
Stretch: Oct&amp;rsquo;16 - Nov&amp;rsquo;16
Complete Project: Deep Reinforcement Learning
Created an AI agent which learnt to play a number of Atari Games and defeated Atari hard-coded AIs, using same set of hyper parameters. Implemented Q Learning algorithm described in seminal papers by Google Deepmind and used a Convolutional Double Dueling Deep Neural Q-network to approximate the Q value function. Used Bellman Equation and followed deep policy network based approach to implement Monte Carlo policy gradients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multichain for Medical Records</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/transaction/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Satyadev Nandakumar, IITK &amp;amp; Dr. Piyush P. Kurur, IITK
Stretch: Aug&amp;rsquo;17 - Nov&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: Blockchain based Smart Transaction Platform
Studied about decentralised databases, database synchronisation, encryption techniques, proof of work, verification rules used by miners and importance of round robin scheduling for miners. Built the database of the platform using MultiChain library incorporating features to create blockchains, streams and perform transactions. Backend was JavaScript based and frontend was HTML5/CSS based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NachOS</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/nachos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/nachos/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Mainak Chaudhuri, IITK
Stretch: Aug&amp;rsquo;16 - Nov&amp;rsquo;16
Complete Project: Extension of NachOS
Implemented fork, join and exec system calls in NachOS-instructional C++ software to run as secondary OS. Compared algorithms for page replacement, process scheduling, demand paging, shared memory and syn-chronisation support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Railway Enquiry System</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/railway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/railway/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Medha Atre, IITK
Stretch: Jan&amp;rsquo;17 - Apr&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: RailQuery
Implemented queries like trains between stations involving optimized parameters such as minimum cost, time or distance using Neo4j. Implemented alogithms like Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s Algorithm and BFS-Traversal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security of Zoobar Server</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/zoobar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/zoobar/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Sandeep Shukla, IITK
Stretch: Jan&amp;rsquo;18 - Apr&amp;rsquo;18
Complete Project: Security of Zoobar Server
Found, exploited and fixed stack overflow, format string, DoS vulnerebilities and various other network layer attacks in the zoobar server. Crafted and demonstrated XSS, SQL injections and numerous browser based attacks on the server using scripts written in C++ and Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacked Attention Network for Visual Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/vqa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/vqa/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Vinay P. Namboodiri, IITK
Stretch: Aug&amp;rsquo;17 - Nov&amp;rsquo;17
Complete Project: Stacked Attention Network
Modified SANs for VQA using Visual Grounding of Phrases. SANs use semantic representation of a question as query to search for the regions in an image that are related to the answer. Implemented a multiple-layer SAN in which we query an image multiple times to infer the answer progressively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task oriented natural language end-to-end dialog system</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/task-oriented-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 18:06:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/task-oriented-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Dr. Harish Karnick, IITK
Stretch: Jan&amp;rsquo;18 - Apr&amp;rsquo;18
Complete Project: Task Oriented Chatbot
Teaching machines to converse naturally with humans to achieve specific tasks is very challenging. Currently, developing task oriented dialogue systems require specific hand-crafting. Also obtaining the dataset may be very cumbersome and costly. As a result, it is very difficult to scale them to new dimensions.The first implementation targets the first problem of specific hand-crafting. The second implementation improves it further by considerably reducing the data required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elanic Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/elanic-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/elanic-intern/</guid>
      <description> NodeJS Development Nov&amp;rsquo;15 - Dec&amp;rsquo;15
Mentor: Pragyan Tripathi, CTO, Elanic
 Full Stack Development: Elasticsearch, MongoDB and NodeJS with Restify framework. Indexed all the data to Elasticsearch from MongoDB and builtREST APIs for search queries.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShareChat Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/sharechat-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/sharechat-intern/</guid>
      <description>Full Stack Development May&amp;rsquo;16 - July&amp;rsquo;16
Mentor: Bhanu Singh, CTO, ShareChat
 Worked on Mixpanel API to get data about the Mobile Application and used D3.js(Data Driven Documents), a data visualisation tool to convert raw data to presentable form. Data included retention and engagement cohorts. Was part of a 3 member team which whose responsibility was making, maintaining and deploying anandroid app which featured as Top Free in the Google Play Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineer at VISA</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-fte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-fte/</guid>
      <description>My Responsibilities at VISA July&amp;rsquo;18 - Present
Manager: Mr. Dumesh Nair, Director of Software Engineering at VISA
 Responsibilities include designing, implementing and maintaining large scale distributed systems used in everyday payment transactions. Worked on detecting the future possibility of deadlock during parallel processing and dynamically changing the resource allocation algorithm. Designed and implemented Least Cost Routing(minimum possible fees paid by VISA) for debit and credit card transactions in a new sale service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VISA Intern</title>
      <link>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 17:51:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhi608.github.io/project/visa-intern/</guid>
      <description>My Projects at VISA Self-Heling Automation May&amp;rsquo;17 - July&amp;rsquo;17
Manager: Mr. Mohan Babu Nellore, Director-MAP
Mentor: Mr. Arup Datta
 Implemented an intelligent automation architecture that makes sure all dependent components (VMs, services/applications, databases) are working as desired before running actual test suite to wipe off all false positives. This ensured that there is no downtimefor any service/API and also reduced development and test time by 90%. Implemented Restful APIs for application health-check, starting/stopping and re-starting the services using JAVA servlet framework.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>